Kohei Ueno (Kohei Hiraga)

Senior Software Engineer at LY Corporation / Node.js Core Collaborator

+81 90-4242-2296 / kohei.ueno119@gmail.com / github.com/cola119

As a Senior Software Engineer with five years of experience at LY Corporation, I specialize in developing SDKs for the widely-used MINI App platform in Asia. My expertise in JavaScript and Web technology is further demonstrated through significant contributions to open-source projects like Node.js and WebKit.

Experience

LY Corporation Senior Software Engineer

Tokyo, Japan April 2023 - Present

- As a tech lead, led a team of 4 Front-End developers and Collaborated with over 15 people (3 project managers, 4 quality assurances, 2 UX designers, and 8 developers from other teams) to build a MINI App platform called LINE Front-End Framework (LIFF) and its authentication infrastructure.
- Developed the JavaScript SDK of the LIFF platform, enabling developers to create web apps on the LINE app, a messenger service operated by LY Corporation with over 150 million daily active users. <u>Link to my talk at the conference by LYCorp about LIFF and developer experience</u>.
- Designed and Developed devtools and CLI tools to enhance the LIFF developer experience.
 Link to my talk at JSConf JP 2021 about DevTools architecture.

LY Corporation Software Engineer

July 2019 - April 2023

- Participated in a panel discussion about the sustainability of open-source software, providing insights from the perspective of a major open-source (Node.js) maintainer. <u>YouTube Link</u>.
- Developed UI components specialized for the LIFF platform using Web Components technology.
- Developed web apps for browsers and the LINE app using SPA frameworks such as React and Vue.js. Focused on optimizing web app performance to ensure a seamless user experience on the LINE app, even for users with non-high-end devices.

Node.js Project Core Collaborator

Remote August 2022 - Present

- Submitted over 40 pull requests to implement new features and fix bugs with a particular focus
 on the `node:inspector` module with my interest and expertise in debugging methodology.
- Mentored individuals interested in Node.js and open-source contributions. Facilitated pair
 programming and code review to enable them to contribute to Node.js and earn
 acknowledgment. <u>Link to LINE Open Source Sprint 2023 report LINE Engineering</u>.

WebKit Individual Contributor

Remote September 2023 - Present

 Submitted over 15 patches, primarily focused on the WebVTT area, leading to a substantial improvement in WebVTT API compatibility from 88.98% to 96.61%. Link to my patch list.

Education

Tokyo Institute of Technology Bachelor's degree, Computer Science April 2015 - March 2019

Proficiencies

Languages: Japanese (Native), English (Fluent), JavaScript, TypeScript, C, C++, HTML, CSS